JOON RUIZ

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST

CONTACT

973 - 289 - 0287

www.linkedin.com/in/joon-ruiz-967611201/

https://github.com/Aecop

SUMMARY

Aspiring Software Developer and DevOps with 7 years of professional IT experience. Currently pursuing an Associate of Science Degree in Computer Technology and hold a CompTIA Network+ certification. Experienced IT Field technician providing excellent customer service and support to end users and clients.

Knowledge in software applications, enterprise level applications, networks and networking systems, and troubleshooting.

Willingness to adapt, a passion for troubleshooting, an eagerness to learn, and an enthusiasm for problem solving.

SPECIALIZED MILITARY TRAINING

Sustainment Automation
 Support Management (SASMO)

- Basic Leader Course (BLS)
- Command Post of the Future (CPOF)

EDUCATION

Software Developer

(University of Washington Bootcamp)

Full Stack Developer

in University of Washington
Projected APR 2023

Associate of Science (AS)

Information Technology
in American Military University
Projected APR 2023

CERTIFICATE

CompTIA Network+ AUG 2021

ETA Fiber Optic Installer SEP 2020

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

- HARDWARE: Cisco Switches, Hard Drives, Juniper Router, Modems, Access Point, Troubleshooting
- SOFTWARE: SharePoint, SolarWinds, Visio, Microsoft Office Suite, MS Azure, MS Team, Active Directory, Troubleshooting
- PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE: Python, PowerShell, HTML, CSS (BootStrap, TailsWindcss), MySQL, MongoDB,
 JavaScript (Node JS, ReactJS, ExpressJS),
- OPERATING SYSTEMS: Mac / Windows 7 & 10
- NETWORKING / PROTOCOLS: LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, VPN, Wi-Fi, Wireless, Switches
- ENTERPRISE APPLICATIONS: Jira/Confluence, Zoom, SIQ(SpaceIQ), Cherwell, MS Intune, Jamf, OpsGenie
- PROCESSES: Change Management, Imaging, OSI Model, Active Directory, User Access and Data Assurance
- SPECIALTIES: Administration, Compliance, Account Management, Access Control, Information Assurance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Clearwater Analytics | AUG 2021 ~ present

- Assigned system permissions and set up computers to assist with onboarding new employees.
- Made sure to meet auditing standards when working with sensitive information.
- Developed and tested new automations using PowerShell and Python to support our team for less manual work.
- Created technical documents to support internal users to reduce manual support.
- Prevented unnecessary downtimes for the user workflow by responding to cases and user issue rapidly.
- Participated with designing new IT help portal for end users to submit cases and issues.
- Maintained and supervised Seattle office with networking issue, zoom rooms, hardware issue, software issue, access points being the only technician.
- Administered end user with correct groups and roles to prevent from violating auditing issue.

DESKTOP TECHNICIAN II

Health Point CHC | MARCH 2021 ~ AUG 2021

- Identified negative hardware performance trends and common issues afflicting systems, reporting findings for remediation.
- Deployed hardware needed for new sites by meeting the time requirements.
- Collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems.
- Solved and fixed the issues and tickets in timely manner 98% of the time.
- Took responsibilities of over \$20k worth of hardware.
- Performed 3 to 4 on-site visit to clinics to provide user support of hardware and software.
- Planned and performed with system administrators with printer upgrades with zero downtime.
- Coached helpdesk technicians with advance technical problems.

United States Army - Various Locations (JBLM and Camp Red Cloud) | MAY 2016 ~ MARCH 2021

FIELD TECHNICIAN (VSAT) / SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

- Utilized safety practices with no complaints or accidents.
- Instructed team members with tasks and responsibilities by weekly.
- Made sure network uptime at least 99% for supporting customers.
- Drafted training materials and organized training sessions for 4 or more supporting companies.
- Instructed team members with tasks and responsibilities by weekly.
- Took responsibilities of over \$100k worth of Army hardware for 2 years without any loss of equipment.
- Troubleshooted and configured 40 very small aperture terminal (VSAT) satellite systems providing network access and internet connectivity for 20+ companies.
- Planned and managed training materials to provide end users basic operation to deploy hardware (VSAT)

HELP DESK TECHNICIAN

- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Provided on-call support for critical issues related to hardware and software.
- Assisted with updating technical support best practices for use by team.
- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for employees.
- Managed customers' expectations of support and technology functionality to provide positive user experience.